christianchildrensfund.org 2018-10-02

# Privacy Policy: ChildFund

We at ChildFund International respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you. This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it when you visit our site (the “Site”) or use our services (collectively the “Services”). Our Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the information you provide to us. We also tell you how you can reach us to update your contact information, remove your name from our mailing lists, or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices.

**We maintain full confidentiality of all sponsors and contributors on our mailing and email lists, which will neither be sold to nor exchanged with any other organization or commercial enterprise, and we honor donors’ opt-out choices in our mail, email, phone and other solicitations.**

We do share some information as described in the section below titled “Information We Share.” By visiting the Site or using any of our Services, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Privacy Notice. Your use of our Site or Services and any dispute over privacy are subject to this Privacy Notice and our General Terms and Conditions, available at http://www.childfund.org/terms_of_use/, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. You registration on our Site and subsequent use of or access to web pages accessible only by registered users is further governed by our Restricted Sites Terms and Conditions available at [http://www.childfund.org/](http://www.childfund.org/).  The General Terms and Conditions and the Restricted Sites Terms and Conditions are incorporated by reference into this Privacy Notice. 

**Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:**

  * Information We Collect and How We Use It
  * Email Communications
  * Send a Postcard to a Friend
  * My Correspondence
  * Donations
  * Questionnaires and Surveys
  * Contests and Games
  * Contact ChildFund International
  * Cookies and Web Beacons
  * Information We Share
  * Links to Other Sites
  * Security
  * Your Choices
  * Updates to This Privacy Notice
  * How to Contact Us

**Information We Collect and How We Use It**

We may collect information about you directly from you and from third parties, as well as automatically through your use of our Site or Services. You may choose to provide personal information (such as your name, address, telephone number and email address) either by phone, mail or on our Site. Certain areas and features of our Site and Services may require registration. To register, you must provide your name, address, email address, login and password. We may also request from you or allow you to submit additional optional information, such as phone number; however, you are not required to provide us with this information.

**Email Communications**

When you ask us to send you email such as a free email newsletter, you may provide us with certain information such as your email address so we can fulfill your request. You may choose to provide additional information as well, such as your postal address and phone number.

**Send a Postcard to a Friend**

If you take advantage of our Send a Postcard to a Friend feature, we ask for your friend’s and your first name and email addresses. We use your friend’s name and email address only to send the information you requested that we forward. We don’t keep your friend’s email address or use it for any other purpose.

**My Correspondence**

If you take advantage of our My Correspondence feature to send and receive Digital Communications to your sponsored child(ren), ChildFund International may screen Digital Communications in your My Correspondence Account consistent with ChildFund International’s internal policies, including but not limited to its policies on child sponsorship correspondence and child protection.  Consistent with its application of such policies, ChildFund International reserves the right to remove, edit, or refuse to transmit or refuse to facilitate transmittal of Digital Communications. ChildFund International, may in its sole discretion, store any Digital Communications in your My Correspondence Account for a commercially reasonable period following the end of your sponsorship relationships through ChildFund International.  You should review the Restricted Sites Terms and Conditions for additional important information regarding the content you upload using the My Correspondence feature. 

**Donations**

When you make a donation through our Site (for example, by sponsoring a child), we may ask you to submit certain personal information (such as credit card information) so we can process your donation. We use the credit card information you provide only to fulfill the transaction you have requested. We maintain that information in our customer service records in the event you choose to make another donation later. We also maintain your contact information in our records so we can contact you to provide ChildFund International program information and information on additional giving opportunities.

**Questionnaires and Surveys**

We occasionally may ask visitors to our Site to complete online surveys and opinion polls about their activities, attitudes and interests. These surveys help us understand the needs of our visitors. We do not keep any personal information about you in connection with your participation in a Site survey unless you specifically agree to provide this information.

**Contests and Games**

Our site occasionally may contain notices of contests or games we are conducting through other sites, which you may enter electronically in some cases. We use the information you provide to conduct the contest or game (for example, to contact you if you are a winner). We won’t use the information you have provided to enter the contest or game for any other purpose unless you’ve agreed otherwise.

**Contact ChildFund International**

You may choose to contact us through our Site. We provide online forms so you may, for example, (1) ask a question, (2) update your address or (3) request more information. We use the information you provide on these forms to fulfill your request. We use the information you provide to respond to your inquiries. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site or Services. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster login process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site and Service. There are two types of cookies: session and persistent cookies.

  * **_Session Cookies._** Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser or turn off your computer. We use session cookies to allow our systems to uniquely identify you during a session or while you are logged in to the Site. This allows us to process your online transactions and requests and verify your identity after you have logged in and as you move through our Site.

  * **_Persistent cookies._** Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you have closed your browser or turned off your computer. We use persistent cookies to track aggregate and statistical information about user activity.

**_Third-Party Cookies._** ****

We may also engage third parties to track and analyze non-personally and personally identifiable Site data. We use the data collected by such third parties to help us administer and improve the quality of the Site and to analyze Site usage. Such third parties may combine the information that we provide about you with other information that they have collected. This Privacy Notice does not cover such third parties’ use of the data.

**_Disabling Cookies._** ****

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function. 

**_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies._** ****

Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content and compile statistics about Site usage. We and our third-party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers, to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed and track whether our emails are forwarded. 

**_Third-Party Analytics._** ****

We use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site and, to the extent permitted, our Application. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Services, performance and user experiences. We do not share your personal information with these third parties.

ChildFund International does not sell, rent, trade or otherwise disclose personal information about our Site visitors (nor our offline donors), except as described here. We share information provided by our Site visitors with service providers that we have retained to perform services on our behalf ― for example, to process donations. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, (ii) in response to a request from law enforcement authorities or other government officials, (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity, or (iv) to our affiliates or subsidiaries.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided through this Site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice.

**_User-Generated Content._** ****

We invite you to post content on our Site. If you post content to our Site, all of the information that you post will be available to all visitors to our Site (except, for example, content posted to Restricted Sites using the My Correspondence feature) . If you post your own content on our Site (including our Restricted Sites) or Services, your posting may become public and ChildFund International cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Privacy Notice, the law or your personal privacy.

**_Links to Other Sites_** ****

Occasionally we provide links to other sites for your convenience and information. These sites operate independently from our site and are not under our control. These sites may have their own privacy notices in place, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked sites. We are not responsible for the content of these sites, any products or services that may be offered through these sites or any other use of these sites.

**Security**

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration or destruction of the personal information in our possession. When you provide credit card information to make a donation, we use the industry standard for Internet security ― Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology ― to help protect the information you provide. This Internet encryption standard scrambles data as it travels from your computer to our server. Please note, however, that perfect security does not exist on the Internet. You’ll know that you’re in a secure area of our Site when a “lock” icon appears on your screen and the “http” portion of our URL address changes to “https.” The “s” stands for “secure.”

**Your Choices**

If you would like to update your contact information or prefer not to receive certain communications from us (such as email), please call or write us using one of the options provided below, or visit [www.childfund.org/contact_us](https://www.childfund.org/contact_us/).

**_Access to My Personal Information._** You may modify personal information that you have submitted by logging in to your account and updating your profile information. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site for a period of time.

**International Users.** If you are accessing the Site or Services from outside the United States, please be advised that your personal information will be transferred to and processed in the United States, a jurisdiction whose data protection laws may not provide equivalent legal protections for your personal information as do the data protection laws in your jurisdiction. You expressly consent to the transfer of your personal information to, and the processing of it in, the United States.

**Updates to This Privacy Notice**

We may change or update portions of this Privacy Notice at any time and without prior notice to you. Please check back from time to time so you are aware of any changes or updates to the Notice. We will indicate below the effective date of the Notice.

**How to Contact Us**

If you would like us to update your contact information or remove your name from our email or postal mailing lists, or if you have any questions about our information practices, please contact us by visiting [www.childfund.org/contact_us](https://www.childfund.org/contact_us/) or calling us at (800) 776-6767 or (804) 756-2700.
